Both HDFC Ago and ICICI LBD are
considered to be the top health insurance providers in the market in
every respect.  HDFC Ago's plan
Optimus Secure and ICIC LBD's plan
Elevate are both the latest plans.  Both are
unique plans and are being used by millions of customers.  The
concept of HDFC Ago is
Four X concept, that is, if you
take a policy of Rs 10 lakh, you will get four times the benefit i.e.
coverage up to Rs 40 lakh.  The
concept of ICIC LBAD Elevate is Infinite
Concept.  Here you will get the options of Infinite Sum
Insured, Infinite Bonus, Infinite
Claim.  It is a completely unique
concept.  So both the plans are
best selling plans in themselves.  And if you are
confused about
which of these plans you should choose for your family, then today I have
brought for you such a comparison which is
easy to understand and simplified.
Here we have divided our discussion into two parts.  First of all,
I will
tell you the coverage that both the plans
cover which diseases and
which expenses they cover.  Many
things are common in it.  In the second part I will
tell you the benefits.  Here you
need to give main focus and to simplify it,
I have divided the benefits into three parts.  The
basic benefits
offered by both these plans will again
match in most cases.  Other
minor benefits that do
n't require much focus.  And the third major benefit in
which both the plans differ from each other.
Where you
need to pay more attention and focus and accordingly
you will have to make your decision.  A short introduction before
going into the discussion and comparison of both the plans.
Mr.
Policy Insurance is a team of health
insurance experts.  We provide end to
end service from policy buying to
claim service to renewal service.  If you are
new to our channel then don't
forget to subscribe and press the bell icon
to get the latest updates.
So let's start the discussion and comparison
of both these pluses.  Optima Secure Plan by HDFC Shares
and Elevate Plan by ICIC LB.
As I said in the beginning,
both the plans are best selling plans.  So they are
loaded with features.  But we have
designed our comparison in such a way that it will be
easy for you to understand and make decisions.
So first of all we will talk about the coverage,
what cover you get in the policy.   We will
discuss two types of coverage here.
Treatment coverage means which
diseases are covered and expenses coverage
means how much expenses you will incur from the policy.
So first of all we will talk about treatment
coverage.  Obviously both the policies will
cover the cost of treatment of illness and accident.
But it has some rules.
What treatments will be covered?  Number one
hospitalization cover.  If we are admitted to the hospital for
24 hours or more,
both the policies will provide you coverage.  Here
is a useful information for you that ICICI
LBD offers you an add on.  Where
you can reduce the 24-hour condition to just two
hours.  So there is an important
useful rider that you can include in your policy.  The
second cover
you will get is Day Procedure Cover.  There are many surgical
procedures that are completed in less than 24
hours.  So all
types of day procedures are covered by both the policies
up to the sum insured.  The third cover
you will get is the cover of Modern Treatment and Robotic
Surgeries.  All types of modern
treatments, all types of robotic surgeries are
covered by both the policies.  That too up to the
sum insured, there is no sub limit.  And the
fourth cover you will get is Domiciliary Cover, Organ
Donor Cover and AYUSH Cover.  AYUSH means
Ayurvedic and Homeopathic cover.  So
both the policies also offer these three covers.
That too up to the sum insured.
Now we come to the second part of coverage,
expenses coverage, which
expenses will the company cover.  There are some rules for this also.
Most of the things
are common here too but one should have information.  First of all,
hospital expenses, when we are
admitted in the hospital, there are 10 types of
expenses there.  Medicines, tests, operation, room,
ICU, all these expenses will be covered under the policy.
Also in HDFC Ago and also in ICC LBA.  The second
expense is room rent and ICU.   There are
no conditions in both the policies.
HDFC Air allows you any room.  That means
you can take a private room, deluxe room or any other
room.  ICIC LBD allows you a single
private basic room.
ICIC LBD offers you a rider if you want.
Where you can upgrade yourself to Any Room category.
Second comes
your pre and post coverage.  HDFC
ARG gives you 60 days of
expenses before admission.  Covers expenses for 180 days after discharge.
ICIC LBA covers your
expenses for 90 days before admission and the
same for 180 days after discharge.
After this your road
ambulance arrives.  Both policies cover your road
ambulance.  Emergency road
ambulance cover up to sum insured.
After that comes your air ambulance.  So
HDFCO by default gives you air ambulance
cover.  ICICI LBT does
not provide air ambulance cover by default.  But they
offer a rider.  Where you can include
air ambulance on your policy at a nominal cost.
So in the discussion so far we talked
about coverage.  Treatment coverage,
expenses coverage.  As you can see,
both plans offer extensive coverage
and the coverage of both plans
is largely common.  90% is common.  There is hardly a difference of 10%
which are minor differences.  So
now let us take the discussion
towards the benefits.  I have also
divided the benefits into three parts.  First of all,
I will tell you the basic and common benefits
that both the policies offer.  Then we will
talk about minor benefits and then we will talk about
major benefits which are the
main differences between both the plans on the basis of which you can
make your decision.
So first of all we will talk
about the basic benefits.  The number one basic
benefit is the bonus benefit, which HDFC
calls plus benefit.  What is bonus benefit is
that the sum insured in your policy
increases.  Your coverage increases.
HDFC Ergo is offering 50% annual bonus.
That means if you take a policy of Rs 10 lakh, you will get a bonus of Rs 5 lakh
next year.  ICIC LBA is also
giving bonus but if you take a policy of 20% per annum i.e. Rs 10
lakh, then you will get a bonus of Rs 2 lakh next year.  The
maximum bonus of HDFC Ergo
is 100% i.e. 50% will be given and next year again
you will get 50% maximum bonus of 100% i.e. the
policy will double.  The maximum bonus of ICIC LBA
is also 100% but it is given on yearly basis at 20%, hence it
takes 5 years.   It will take
you 5 years to increase from Rs 10 lakh to Rs 20 lakh.
Now let me tell you the conditions of the bonus.  The
bonus of HDFC Arco
is guaranteed.  That means it will be available even after making a claim.  You will get it even if you do
not claim it.  And
HDFC's bonus is permanent.  This means that the
bonus will not be reversed even after claiming it.
ICICI LB bonus is not guaranteed.  If
you have taken the claim then you will not get the bonus
and if you do not take the claim then you will get the bonus.
But it is irreversible.  This means that the bonus
added by the company to your policy will
not be reversed upon claim.   The
second basic benefit is the restore or reset
benefit.  HDFC and we call it
restore and ICICI in the government call
it reset.  What is this benefit?  Yearn at 100%.
That is, the benefit is equal to the number of lakhs of the policy. If the
policy is of Rs. 10 lakh, then Rs. 10
lakh can be restored. Both HDFCO and ICIC LB
companies offer 100%
restore benefit in the policy and that too unlimited
times. That is, if Rs. 10 lakh is exhausted, you will get Rs.
10 lakh again and if that too is exhausted, you will get it for the
third time. If it is exhausted for the third time, you will get it for the
fourth time. You will get it unlimited number
of times. There is
no condition on this benefit in both the policies.  That
means you can restore for the same person with the same disease
and
you can also use this restore option for different persons with different diseases.  That
means this benefit is
exactly the same in both the policies.   The
third basic benefit is the annual health checkup
benefit.  HDFC Ago is offering you a health checkup every year.
Its limit ranges from ₹5,000 to ₹10,000.
This company offers this every year except the first year.
ICIC LB plan does not offer annual health checkup by default.
But the
company offers an add-on rider which you
can choose and you can add annual health checkup
to your policy.  HDFC Ergo's
annual health checkup is done on a reimbursement basis.  This
means that you can get it done anywhere as per your wish
and you have to file its bills and
reports with the company
and the company pays you back the reimbursement.
Health checkup is cashless at ICICI LBA.   That
means you have to book through customer care from the company's mobile app.
You do
not have to make any payment and
this process is completed cashless.   The
next important basic benefit is
cover for non-consumable expenses.  HDFCO covers
non-consumable expenses by default in its policies.
You do
not need to get any separate add-on or rider.  The
ICICI LBD Elevate plan does
not cover non-consumable expenses by default.
But the company
offers a rider called Claim Protector which you
can include in your policy.
After that, non-consumer expenses will be covered in your policy.
So this way
we discussed the basic benefits that both the
companies are offering.  Some have a little less
, some have a little more.  But
both companies offer these basic benefits.
In some cases, you may have to get an add-on.
But otherwise all the basic
benefits are available in both the pluses.
After discussing the basic benefits, now I will
discuss with you the minor benefits or
minor differences.  Number one doctor e
consultation.  There is no doctor consultation facility through HDFC Ago app.
But through the mobile app of ICIC LBD, you get
unlimited number of times doctor
consultation every year.  Another
minor difference is the wellness discount.  HDFCO does
not offer any wellness discount on renewal premium.  But ICIC LBAD
offers a wellness discount that can get you up to 30% off
on renewal premium.
Subject to this, you should achieve the
fitness targets or goals of the company.  The
third minor difference is the
OPD rider.  Both policies offer OPD rider.
In HDFC Ago its name is
Optima Well Being and in ICICI LB its
name is Be Fit.  There is a slight difference between the two.
HDFC Ergo's Optima Well
Being Rider provides doctor
consultation both telephonically and in-person.
ICIC LBT's Bfit Rider gives us doctor
consultation telephonically and in-person.
Apart from this, it also covers diagnostic tests
and pharmacy.  The
fourth minor difference is maternity cover.
Again, both the policies offer a rider of maternity cover.
Again there is a slight difference.
HDFCO has a waiting period of two years
for maternity cover.  ICICI LAT also has a
waiting period of two years.  So the difference is
in the amount of coverage.  HDFC Ago
gives you four options.  You can choose between Rs 500, Rs 1 lakh, Rs 1.5 lakh
and Rs 2 lakh.
Your premium will be charged accordingly.  And ICICI LBD gives
you 10% of sum insured.  That means
you will get maternity cover worth 10% of the policy amount
subject to a maximum of ₹1 lakh.
Now we come to the last
but most important part of the discussion where we will talk
about the major benefits.  These are the
benefits that make both the plans different and
unique and chances are
that on the basis of one of these you
will decide which plan you want to take for your family.
So first of all let's talk about
HDFCO.  The major benefit that HDFC Ago
is offering is Secure Cover.   If
you take a policy with 100% of sum insured i.e. Rs 10 lakh, then a
secure cover of Rs 1 lakh will be
added to your policy from day one.  That means
you will take a policy of Rs 10 lakh but the company will
give you a limit of Rs 20 lakh from day one.  The company is also offering another option in this.
Its name is Super Secure
Cover.  If you take a policy of Rs 10 lakh, you will get 200%
secure cover.  You will have a policy of Rs 10 lakh.  There will be a
secure cover of Rs 20 lakh.   The
company is providing you a total limit of Rs 30 lakh from day one.
ICC Low LMAT plans do not offer any feature called Secure Cover.
So this is the biggest major benefit of HDFC
where you pay a premium of Rs 10 lakh
but you can get a cover of Rs 1 lakh or Rs 1 lakh
due to secure cover.
If HDFC is offering 100% or 200% secure cover, then
ICICI LBA is also not far behind.
They also have many major benefits that
work on the Infinite team.  First of all,
ICICI LBAT offers Infinite Sum
Insured i.e. Unlimited Sum Insured.   That
means you do not have to choose 10 lakh, 20 lakh, 50 lakh.
Your policy
offers unlimited sum insured by default.
Any claim we make, be it of Rs 50 lakh, Rs 1 crore or Rs
5 crore, will be passed through the policy
because we have taken unlimited infinite sum
insurance.  The second company offers an
infinite bonus called Power
Booster.  That means a bonus of 100% will be
added to your policy every year.  That too up
to infinite unlimited level.  That means there
is no maximum limit.  If you take a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then
every year Rs 10 lakh will be
added to your policy.
₹1 lakh will be
added to your policy every year as long as you continue the policy.  And this bonus is also
regardless of claim.  Even if we make a claim, we will still
get the bonus.  If you don't make a claim then you will
obviously get it.  The third
infinite feature the company offers.  Its
name is Infinite Care.  Or we can understand it as an
infinite claim.  This
means that thanks to this feature,
once in life when we
are stuck in a big trouble, we
can use this option and our
unlimited amount of claim will be passed on to the company.
So when we are in such a big crisis or
tragedy, then this feature comes in handy for us
and our unlimited claim gets passed by the company.
So this entire plan is based on the theme of infinity.  The
company is offering three infinite features.  Infinite Sum
Insured, Infinite Bonus and Infinite
Claim.
Now I will talk about another major benefit
called PED Rider i.e.
Pre-Existing Disease Rider.  Both
HDFC and ICICI companies offer this rider.
This rider in HDFC works
for four diseases.  Asthma, BP, Sugar and
Cholesterol.  The company says that
if we have any of these four diseases and we
take a policy from HDFC, then we will not have to
wait for three years for these diseases.
These diseases will be covered in our policy from the very first day
and we will get the claim.  ICICI
Rombert also offers this rider.  Here
it is called Jump Start Rider.  But it
offers it for six diseases.  People suffering from BP,
sugar, asthma and cholesterol do it.  The
company also offers riders in cases of obesity and heart strength.  This
means that despite these six pre-existing
conditions, we will get cover for these diseases from the beginning.  The
slight difference
here in ICICI is that in ICICI this
chronic disease cover will not be zero.  It will be for 30
days.  That means from the 31st day the
policy will offer you cover for these six diseases.  So these
were the three major benefits of these policies which
make these policies different.  Secure
cover that HDFC offers.
Features of Infinite which ICICI does not offer are Infinite
Sum Insured Infinite Bonus Infinite
Claim which ICIC offers and HDFC does
not offer and lastly PED Rider which
both offer but there
is a slight difference.
But even after discussing so many important things,
our discussion is incomplete and our
decision making will remain incomplete because
any
health insurance policy decision
making cannot be done only on the basis of coverage and benefits.
Every discussion and every decision making
is incomplete without premium.  So, if you also want to know the premium
of both these policies Optima Secure and
Elevate for your family, then you
can type the premium in the comment section.
Apart from this,
if you have any query regarding the features of the plan, you
can also comment.  Our team will
respond to you quickly and that too completely
free of cost.  Stay connected
with Mr. Policy.  Like, share and subscribe for such useful and informative videos.
Thank you for watching.